Scenic Hudson Collection: Records Relating to the Storm King Case, 1963-1981
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Scenic Hudson Collection: Records relating to the Storm King Case, 1963-1981
Scenic Hudson, Inc.
NPKMC-221-183
74 Linear Feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Scenic Hudson, Inc., formerly Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, was founded in 1963 to oppose the Consolidated Edison Company’s proposed pumped storage facility at Storm King Mountain, near Cornwall, New York. The records consist of correspondence, legal documents, transcripts of hearings, agenda and minutes of meetings, memoranda, studies, reports, publicity materials, printed matter, clippings, photographs, and audiovisual materials.
Acquisitions Information
Scenic Hudson, Inc. presented the records to the Marist College Library in 1982.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Related Collections
Historical Note
In September 1962, the Consolidated Edison Company announced plans to build a pumped storage facility, the largest of its kind in the world, at Storm King Mountain near Cornwall, New York. The initial application for license to construct the plant was filed with the Federal Power Commission in January 1963. On November 8, 1963, a small group of concerned citizens met at the home of Carl Carmer and formed the Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference to fight the pumped storage project on the grounds that it posed a threat to the Cornwall water supply and Hudson River fisheries as well as to scenic and historic Storm King Mountain. The case lasted for 17 years. In a negotiated settlement in December 1980, Consolidated Edison agreed to drop the plan for the Storm King facility. In the meantime, Scenic Hudson emerged at the forefront of the environmental movement. Over the past thirty-five years, Scenic Hudson, Inc. has safeguarded over 18,000 acres of irreplaceable landscapes, protected productive farmland, reclaimed and transformed neglected industrial waterfront sites, and purchased strategic properties to revive community centers.
Carl Carmer, author of The Hudson River and other historic works, became honorary chairman and Leo O. Rothchild was named chairman. Rothchild served until 1968 and was succeeded by Alexander Saunders. Initially, the members, working in their own homes or borrowed office space, contacted friends, prominent citizens, politicians, and other organizations for financial support, letter writing campaigns, and legal intervention.
The organizations grew rapidly. Contributions were channeled through the Natural Area Council until Scenic Hudson was incorporated in 1974. Rod Vandivert became the executive director in the mid-1960s. An office was set up in New York City, but the location changed several times during Storm King case and there were a number of office managers during that period. Professional fundraisers and public relations firms were employed in later years.
Aided by other organizations and individuals, the group conducted an intensive campaign to educate the public and to deter Consolidated Edison by legal means. The records, which document the organization’s activities, include publicity materials, copies of legal documents submitted by Scenic Hudson and others, and transcripts of hearings before Congressional sub-committees and the Federal Power Commission. The case lasted for 17 years. In a negotiated settlement in December 1980, Consolidated Edison agreed to drop the plan for the Storm King facility.
The lengthy and controversial case set important precedents in environmental law and is generally credited with spawning the modern environmental movement. Scenic Hudson, Inc. continues to serve as an environmental watchdog in the Hudson Valley.
Collection Overview
The Scenic Hudson Collection consists of materials documenting the landmark environmental law case that opposed the Consolidated Edison Company’s proposed pump storage facility at Storm King Mountain, near Cornwall, NY. The Scenic Hudson Decision, as the case is called in law books, launched the modern environmental movement.
The records consist of correspondence, legal documents, transcripts of hearings, agenda and minutes of meetings, memoranda, studies, reports, publicity materials, printed matter, clippings, photographs, and audiovisual materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into 20 series: 1.Consolidated Edison Company, 2. General Correspondence, 3. Feeral Energy Reulatory Commission, 4. Federal Power Commission, 5. Fund Raising and Related Materials, 6. Hearings, 7. Ledoux, Louis Pierre, 8. Legal Papers, 9. Meetings, 10. Other organizations and Individuals Concerned with the Storm King Case, 11. Printer Matteer, 12. Public Service Commission, 13. Sherwood, Helen, 14. Studies, Reports, Statements, Notes, Drafts, and Background Materials, 15. Subject Files, 16. Publicity Materials, 17. Clippings, 18. Oversize Materials, 19. Card File, 20. Audiovisual Materials.
Materials in these series are organized either alphabetically or chronologically.
Deatiled Description of the Collection
- 1. Consolidated Edison Company, 1963-1976; 1; About 3 linear feet Boxes: 1 - 9 Folders: 1 - 102
  Series contains advertising, annual reports, clippings, correspondence, legal briefs and petitions, publicity materials, releases and reports, and subject files relating to the Storm King case.
  Alphabetical
  - Advertising, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Advertising, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alternatives (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1962-1971, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Astoria Plant (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clippings prior to 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings - General, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - World Journal Tribune and New York Times Clippings, February, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General - Clippings, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cornwall, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cornwall Plant, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Clippings from Middletown Herald Record, et. al., 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bradford, Cornwall District Attorney, Paid by Consolidated Edison, Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1966 and Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fort Slocum (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gas Conservation Kit (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Hall, Peter - Middletown Times-Herald (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Historic Hudson (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Interconnections (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Amendment to Application for License, September, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Brief before Federal Power Commission, June 13, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Reply Brief, June 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Brief on Exceptions, August 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Brief before Joint Legislation Committee, December 1, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Answer to Petitions of Cortland Conservation Association and L.I. Fisherman’s Association, December 31, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Opinion and Order… Additional Evidence on Fish Protective Facilities, March 3, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Answer to Scenic Hudson for Stay of Opinion, April 19, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Answer to Motion by Scenic Hudson to Reopen Proceedings, April 19, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Answer to Town of Carmel Petition for Permission to Intervene, Aprl 28, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Opposition to Hempstead Town Lands Resources Council Petition to Intervene, May 3, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Brief before the Federal Power Commission, June 11, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Answer to Petition of Scenic Hudson, et. al. to Reopen Proceeding, June 14, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Reply Brief and Motion to Strike Portion of Scenic Hudson Brief, June 18, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Opposition to Motion of Philipstown Citizens Association to Strike Point III, June 28, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Re Brief Rebutting Point 1C of the Commission Staff Reply Brief, June 18, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Exhibits and Testimony on Behalf of Con Ed, Book (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Exhibits and Testimony on Behalf of Con Ed, Book 2 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Exhibits and Testimony on Behalf of Con Ed, Book 3 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Answer to Motion Filed by Scenic Hudson, April 15, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Amendment to Application for License, May 24, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Answer to Motion by Scenic Hudson and Sierra Club, June 3,1966 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Answer to Motion for Adjustment of Dates, June 29, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Motion for Date for Filing of Testimony, etc. by Opposition, June 29, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Response to Scenic Hudson Inquiries, July 14, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Response to Scenic Hudson Motion to Postpone Hearings, December 14, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Gas Case before FPC, April 11, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Answer to Petition of Connecticut to Intervene, July 28, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Brief After Further Hearings on Remand, August 14, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Answer to Board of Fisheries and Game (Connecticut), August 16, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Reply Brief After Further Hearings on Remand, September 5, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Answer to Scenic Hudson re Extension of Time, August 6, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Brief on Exceptions, October 7, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Response to NYC Petition>, November 4, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Answer to Scenic Hudson, December 30, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Corrections to Official Testimony, March 4, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Response to Scenic Hudson Motion re Computer Runs, November, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Motion to Defer Hearings, December, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Release on Fisheries Study, August 17, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Release on Texas Instrument Study, March 1, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Exhibit L [Catskill Aqueduct] (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Exhibit 464 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Exhibit 508 - Gas Turbines (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Material re Hearings (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Material re Hearings (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Material re Hearings (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Material re Hearings (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Charles F. Luce (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Alexander Lurkis (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Marcus-Itkin Trial, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Middletown Times-Herald (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Nuclear Plants (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - 10 Year Plan (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Press Conference on New Sites, November, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Pro-Consolidated Edison Statements (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - 20-Year Program, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Prospectuses (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Publicity Materials (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Publicity Materials (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Publicity Materials (Financial and General) (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Publicity Materials (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Rates, 1964-1969 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Rates, August 25, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Rates, Clippings, 1966-1969 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Rates, Senator Paul Bookson (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Rate Comparisons with Other Leading Utilities (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Releases and Reports, c. 1964 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Releases and Reports, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Releases and Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Releases on Con Ed, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Releases on Con Ed, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Releases on Con Ed, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Releases on Con Ed, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - Reprints (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Louis H. Roddis, Jr. - Statement, October 23, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Louis H. Roddis, Jr. - Talks on MHD and Unconventional Power Sources (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Stockholder Letters (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Storm King (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Statements re Storm King, 1966-1970 (Box 9, Folder 102)
- 2. General Correspondence, 1964-1974; 2; About 5 linear feet Boxes: 10 - 25 Folders: 103 - 265
  Incoming and outgoing correspondence and memoranda between Scenic Hudson members concerning the Storm King case, inquiries from the general public, and acknowledgments of contributions, arranged in rough alphabetical order. Correspondentsinclude Brooks Atkinson, Walter Boardman, Larry Bogart, Robert Boyle, David Brower,James Buckley, Albert K. Butzel, James Cagney, Thomas P. Callahan, Carl Carmer, James Cope, Ronald Dagon, M. A. Darville, Henry Diamond, Michael J. Donahue, John Dow, Mr. and Mrs. Stephen Duggan, Lou Frankel, Benjamin Frazier, Lloyd Garrison, Robert Glode, Harold L. Oram, Inc., Richard E. Harrison, Hudson River Valley Commission, Jacob K. Javits, President and Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson, Harry J. Kangieser, Kenneth B. Keating, Lawrence E. Kennedy, Jr., W. M. Kitzmiller, Mr. and Mrs. Richard Lamb, Pierre Ledoux, Norman P. Lent, John Lindsay, Charles F. Luce, Alexander Lurkis, Thomas Macres, Mrs. Lee Mieczkowski, Frank D. O’Connor, Richard Ottinger, Henry D. Paley, Philips-town Citizens Association, Dominick Pirone, R. Watson Pomeroy, Frank Potter, Richard Purdue, Susan Reed, Charles Reich, Nelson Rockefeller, Nicholas Roosevelt, Kay Rorimer, Leo Rothchild, Fynette Rowe, Alexander Saunders, Catryna Seymour, Whitney Seymour, Dr. Donald Shaughnessy, Helen Sherwood, Corneliea Otis Skinner, Godfrey Stamm, Calvin Stillman, Esty Stowell, Joseph Swidler, John Tamsen, Herbert Tenzer, Rod Vandivert, and John W. Wydler.
  Roughly Alphabetical
  - A- Am (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - An- Az (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Atkinson, Brooks (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Ba (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Be (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Bi (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Bl (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Bo (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - Boardman Walter (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Bogart, Larry Anti- Pollution League (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Boyle, Robert- “The Hudson River” (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Br (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Brower, David (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Bu- By (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Buckley, James (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Butzel, Albert K (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - Ca (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Cagney, James (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Callahan, Thomas P., 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Callahan, Thomas P., 1965-1969 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Carmer, Carl (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Ce (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Ch- C (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Cl (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Co (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Cope, James, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Cope, James, January - March, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 129)
  - Cope, James, April - July, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 130)
  - Cope, James, August 1967 - 1972 (Box 12, Folder 131)
  - Cope, James Miscellaneous and Undated (Box 12, Folder 132)
  - Cr- Cy (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - Cruthers, Marge (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - Da (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - Dagon, Ronald (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Darville, M.A. (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - De (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Di (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - Diamond, Henry (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Do (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Donahue, Michael J. Mayor of Cornwall (Box 13, Folder 142)
  - Dow, John (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Dr- Dy (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Duggan, Stephen P and Smokie (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - E (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Fa- Fl (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Fo-Fu (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Frankel, Lou -Incoming and Outgoing Corres. (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Frankel, Lou -Interoffice Memoranda (Box 14, Folder 150)
  - Frankel, Lou -Breif re S.H.P.C. Reports (Box 14, Folder 151)
  - Frankel, Lou -re Power (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Frazier, Benjamin W (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Ga (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Garrison, Lloyd [scenic Hudson, Inc. Attorney] (Box 14, Folder iso15511)
  - Garrison, Lloyd [scenic Hudson, Inc. Attorney] (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - Garrison, Lloyd K. III (Box 15, Folder 157)
  - Garrison and Butzel, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 158)
  - Garrison and Butzel, 1970 -71 (Box 15, Folder 159)
  - Ga- Go (Box 15, Folder 160)
  - Glode, Robert (Box 15, Folder 161)
  - Goddess, Lynn (Box 15, Folder 162)
  - Gr- Gu (Box 16, Folder 163)
  - Ha (Box 16, Folder 164)
  - Harold L Oram, Inc (Box 16, Folder 165)
  - Harrison, Richard E. -cartographer (Box 16, Folder 166)
  - He- Hi (Box 16, Folder 167)
  - Ho- Hu (Box 16, Folder 168)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (Box 16, Folder 169)
  - I (Box 16, Folder 170)
  - Interoffice Memoranda (Box 16, Folder 171)
  - Interoffice Memos- proposed program, Hudson Valley Project, May - July, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 172)
  - Interoffice Memos- proposed program, Hudson Valley Project, August 1964-1966 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - J (Box 17, Folder 174)
  - Javits, Jacob K (Box 17, Folder 175)
  - Johnson, Pres. And Mrs. L.B. (Box 17, Folder 176)
  - K (Box 17, Folder 177)
  - Kangieser, Harry J (Box 17, Folder 178)
  - Keating, Kenneth B (Box 17, Folder 179)
  - Kennedy, Lawrence E, Jr (Box 17, Folder 180)
  - Kitzmiller, W.M. (Box 17, Folder 181)
  - La- Le (Box 17, Folder 182)
  - Lamb, Richard and Julia (Box 17, Folder 183)
  - Lamb, Julia -Misc Notes, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 184)
  - Lamb, Julia -Miscellaneous Notes, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 185)
  - Ledoux, Pierre -Hudson Valley Project, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 186)
  - Ledoux, Pierre -Hudson Valley Project, January-September, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 187)
  - Ledoux, Pierre, October 1966-1974 (Box 18, Folder 188)
  - Lent, Norman F (Box 18, Folder 189)
  - Letter Campaign, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 190)
  - Letters to Editors, 1964-1967 (Box 18, Folder 191)
  - Letters to Editors, 1964-1967 (Box 19, Folder 192)
  - Li- Ly (Box 19, Folder 193)
  - Lindsay, John (re Air Pollution) (Box 19, Folder 194)
  - Luce, Charles F (Box 19, Folder 195)
  - Lurkis, Alexander (Box 19, Folder 196)
  - Lurkis, Alexander -Memoranda and Analyses (Box 19, Folder 197)
  - Mac- Mc (Box 20, Folder 198)
  - Ma- Mi (Box 20, Folder 199)
  - Macres, Thomas -Environment II (Box 20, Folder 200)
  - Mathews, Nancy (Box 20, Folder 201)
  - Mieczkowski, Mrs. Lee (Box 20, Folder 202)
  - Mo- My (Box 20, Folder 203)
  - Na (Box 20, Folder 204)
  - NBC news (Box 20, Folder 205)
  - Ne- Nu (Box 20, Folder 206)
  - New York State Agencies (Box 20, Folder 207)
  - Newspapers (Box 20, Folder 208)
  - Newspapers (Box 20, Folder 209)
  - O (Box 21, Folder 210)
  - O’Connor, Frank D (Box 21, Folder 211)
  - Ottinger, Richard (Box 21, Folder 212)
  - Pa- Pe (Box 21, Folder 213)
  - Paley, Henry D (Box 21, Folder 214)
  - Ph- Pl (Box 21, Folder 215)
  - Philipstown Citizens’ Assoc. (Box 21, Folder 216)
  - Pirone, Dominick (Box 21, Folder 217)
  - Po- Pu (Box 21, Folder 218)
  - Hudson Valley Project, January-August, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 219)
  - Hudson Valley Project, September-December, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 220)
  - Robert R Barry, M.C. -Bill, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 221)
  - Hudson Valley Project, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 222)
  - Hudson Valley Project, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 223)
  - Pomeroy, R. Watson, 1964-1966 (Box 22, Folder 224)
  - Pomeroy, R. Watson Witnesses (Box 22, Folder 225)
  - Potter, Frank (Box 22, Folder 226)
  - Purdue, Richard (Box 22, Folder 227)
  - Q (Box 22, Folder 228)
  - Ra -Ri (Box 22, Folder 229)
  - Reed, Susan (Box 22, Folder 230)
  - Reich, Charles (Box 22, Folder 231)
  - Ro- Ry (Box 23, Folder 232)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson (Box 23, Folder 233)
  - Roosevelt, Nicholas (Box 23, Folder 234)
  - Rorimer, Kay (Box 23, Folder 235)
  - Rothschild, Leo (Box 23, Folder 236)
  - Rowe, Fynetta (Box 23, Folder 237)
  - Sa -Se (Box 23, Folder 238)
  - Saunders, Alexander (Box 23, Folder 239)
  - Seymour, Catryna -Fund Raising Booklet (Box 23, Folder 240)
  - Seymour, Whitney N. Jr. (Box 23, Folder 241)
  - Sh- Sl (Box 23, Folder 242)
  - Shaughnessy, Dr. Donald (Box 24, Folder 243)
  - Sherwood, Helen (Box 24, Folder 244)
  - Sherwood, Helen -copies of materials (Box 24, Folder 245)
  - Skinner, Cornelia Otis (Box 24, Folder 246)
  - Sm -Sq (Box 24, Folder 247)
  - St -Sz (Box 24, Folder 248)
  - Stamm, Godfrey (Box 24, Folder 249)
  - Stillman, Calvin W. (Box 24, Folder 250)
  - Stowell, Esty (Box 24, Folder 251)
  - Swidler, Joseph C (Box 24, Folder 252)
  - T (Box 24, Folder 253)
  - Tamsen, John (Box 24, Folder 254)
  - Tenzer, Herbert (Box 24, Folder 255)
  - U (Box 25, Folder 256)
  - Unidentified (Box 25, Folder 257)
  - V (Box 25, Folder 258)
  - Vandivert, Rod (Box 25, Folder 259)
  - Vandivert, Rod (Box 25, Folder 260)
  - Wa -We (Box 25, Folder 261)
  - Wh -Wl (Box 25, Folder 262)
  - Wo -Wr (Box 25, Folder 263)
  - Wydler, John W (Box 25, Folder 264)
  - X -Y -Z (Box 25, Folder 265)
- 3. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, 1965-1981; 3; About 1 linear feet Boxes: 26 - 27 Folders: 266 - 290
  Series contains correspondence, interrogatories, responses, petitions, motions, analyses, reports, and depositions, 1965-1981, arranged chronologically.
  Chronological
  - 2338, 1965-1977 (Box 26, Folder 266)
  - 2338 Correspondence, Interrogatories, Responses, March-August, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 267)
  - 2338 Correspondence, Interrogatories, Responses, September-December, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 268)
  - 2338 Order of Presiding Judge on petition to intervene, September 5, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 269)
  - 2338 Motions re pre -hearing conference, October 20-30, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 270)
  - 2338 FERC Staff rec. re 404 permit/ SHPC ans, December 4-15, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 271)
  - 2338 Report of Presiding Judge - Status of Proc., December 5, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 272)
  - 2338 SHPC/HRFA Petition to terminate or reopen, December 7, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 273)
  - 2338 Correspondence, Interrogatories, Responses, January-June, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 274)
  - 2338 Correspondence, Interrogatories, Responses, July-December, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 275)
  - 2338 1/79 NYS DEC answer to SHPC/HRFA Petition 12/78, January, 1979 (Folder 276, Box 26)
  - 2338 1/18/79 PSC Answer to SHPC/HRFA Petition 12/78, January 18, 1979 (Folder 277, Box 26)
  - 2338 1/18/79 Con Ed answer to SHPC/HRFA Petition 12/78, January 18, 1979 (Folder 278, Box 26)
  - 2338 1/19/79 Dept of Interior Answer to SHPC/HRFA Petition, January 19, 1979 (Folder 279, Box 26)
  - 2338 1/26/79 FERC STAFF Answer To SHPC/HRFA Petition 12/78, January 26, 1979 (Folder 280, Box 27)
  - 2338 2/5/79 SHPC/HRFA Ans. To intervenors responses to Petit, February 5, 1979 (Folder 281, Box 27)
  - 2338 LMS Model and Review and Analysis, April-May 31, 1979 (Folder 282, Box 27)
  - 2338 Tex. Inst. Report Efficiency of 100 ft. Beach Sein estimating densities, July, 1970 (Folder 283, Box 27)
  - 2338 Motion to supplement FERC staff response, July 25, 1970 (Folder 284, Box 27)
  - 2338 Comments on motion to supplement FERC St. res., August, 1979 (Folder 285, Box 27)
  - 2338 Evindetiary Depositions, 1979 (Folder 286, Box 27)
  - 2338 Correspondence Interrogatories, Responses, 1980 (Folder 287, Box 27)
  - 2338 “Baslow Documents”, February 1-November 6, 1980 (Folder 288, Box 27)
  - 2338 Subpoena and Depositions, January-November 26, 1980 (Folder 289, Box 27)
  - 2338 Suspension of Proceedings, Januar 14, February 4, 1981 (Folder 290, Box 27)
- 4. Federal Power Commission, 1964-1978; 4; About 4 linear feet Boxes: 28 - 40 Folders: 291 - 551
  Series contains briefs, opinions, and petitions, arranged chronologically; exhibits; studies; publicity releases; reports, statements; correspondence; clippings; and printed matter relating to hearings before the FPC
  - Opinion and Order Adopting Examiner’s Order, July 30, 1964 (Folder 291, Box 28)
  - Commission Staff Brief Opposing Exception, Sept. 8, 1964 (Folder 292, Box 28)
  - Con Ed Oral Argument, Nov 17, 1964 (Folder 293, Box 28)
  - Rejection of Petition of Intervention of Village of Freeport, Feb. 3, 1965 (Folder 294, Box 28)
  - Original FPC License, Mar. 9, 1965 (Folder 295, Box 28)
  - Notice of Alternative Overhead Transmission Line Routes, Mar. 26, 1965 (Folder 296, Box 28)
  - Order Permitting Intervention to Village of Freeport, Mar. 30, 1965 (Folder 297, Box 28)